[♪♪♪]
Recognize
this banner mount, Zanth?
I wielded one just like it
when we rode into
the Battle of Two Skies.
[grumbling roar]
[chuckling]
So, I'm glad to have guests.
Tea?
Actually, Arrakore,
we have to get to a place
called the Cave of Tones
and wake a dragon,
or, like, half a dragon?
We don't know if it's
the front half or the back half.
Aw, Sora, please.
You'd only need to wake
the Arc Dragon
if you were going up against
the Shatter Dragon of Chaos,
which, I mean... [laughing]
good luck if that ever happens,
b-because--
Oh.
For real?
You're fighting ThunderFang?
Well, that's tough,
Oh, but at least he didn't die
and go to the Spectral Lands,
where his power could...
[chuckling]
[grumbling sadly]
Oh, he did?
Well, you know...
good luck anyway, I guess?
Please tell me you've restored
enough of Djinjago
that the Cave of Tones is back.
[Arrakore] I sure have.
Right there,
but there's
no half-dragon in it.
[groaning] Ugh!
Why not?
My wish magic isn't yet
strong enough
to bring back living things,
like the Arc Dragon,
or my people,
so I've had to settle
for reviving
our cultural artifacts.
The upside?
I've brought back
some really excellent pottery.
The workmanship!
Delilah doesn't like
to be moved!
I told you,
it gets pretty lonely.
Maybe all your magic needs
is the right motivation,
like saving the world.
Arrakore, I wish
for the Arc Dragon of Focus
to be restored.
[breathing deeply]
Your wish is yours to keep...
maybe.
Actually, with Zanth's
new boost of Djinjagan magic,
we might have enough power...
if we work together.
[grumbling roar]
A wish of this magnitude
will take time
and complete concentration.
That means no distractions.
Even loud noises
could destroy our focus
and ruin the wish.
The world hangs in the balance,
so you won't hear a peep
from us.
We're Ninja.
Stealth is our thing.
[metal clanking]
These metal shoes
are not comfortable,
but I like the noise they make!
Clang! Clang!
[clanking]
What?
Did I miss something?
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[thunderclap]
Aah!
[gasping for breath]
[groaning]
[Ras] Leaving you alone,
defenseless,
gone on more important business.
Does it hurt to realize
the Ninja
care so little for you?
[Sora and Frak]
♪ Da-da-da-da-da... ♪
No, it-it's... ♪ Da-da ♪
[grumbling]
It-it's... ♪ Da-Da ♪
You go--you go up after.
♪ Bum-ba-ba-bum-bum
Bum-bum! ♪
Shush!
[whispering] Oh, right.
How are we supposed
to remember this boring song
if we can't make any noise?
[novelty car horn
blaring "La Cucaracha"]
No, you're way off.
That wasn't me.
[novelty car horn blaring]
Rapton lives!
Shh!
Shushing Rapton?
How rude!
What are you goons doing here?
Thievin'.
All this Djinjago loot
is Djinja-going
home with us! Heh.
So, why are we whispering?
Because... these relics
belong to a powerful Djinn
asleep in that cave.
He'll be real angry
if he wakes up.
Huh, okay,
an angry Djinn would cut into
Rapton's profit margin.
[sighing]
Freebooters,
spread out and grab
all the treasure you can,
quiet-like,
but remember,
if you find that jeweled box,
it belongs to me.
We can't let you
steal this stuff.
There's time to fight.
[powering weapons]
What about noise?
[scoffing] Everyone knows
Rapton is a Mighty
Combat Panther of Stealth!
[groaning with impact]
[whispering] Attack!
[gasping]
[boulder thudding]
No gem-stealing, nin-joker!
Hold up, big guy. We--
[clearing throat]
...I mean, I...
I don't want your gems,
because it's just me.
I just need into the cave
behind there
to ring bells,
or else the world
will be destroyed.
World destroyed?
But PowerLid needs world!
That's where PowerLid
keeps his gems!
Oh, no!
PowerLid just said out loud
where he keeps gems.
Anyone could've heard.
Security risk!
Uh... okay,
so I'll just go in.
Yes, little bi-clops,
you go save world.
Only cost you four gems.
You're charging me?
To save the world?
I demand you let me pass!
"Demand"?
Great!
Now cost eight gems!
PowerLid practice surge pricing
at times of peak demand.
But I don't have any gems!
Then kiss rock!
[gasping]
[Kai] Leave my sister alone!
[♪♪♪]
Kai?
What are you doing here?
I came to help!
Sora and Wyldfyre
told me Jerk-face Jay bailed,
and you're doing
a mission alone.
Nice coconut.
Not so bad yourself, handsome.
[PowerLid] Gandy?
That you?
Nope. Uh, uh...
No, no, PowPow,
just a normal,
non-magical coconut.
Stop lie, Gandy.
It been a while,
but PowerLid recognize voice
of former BFF anywhere,
and it good to see you again,
because now PowerLid
will get revenge!
[roaring ferociously]
[clattering outside]
[clanking loudly]
[tiptoes pattering,
low growling]
[soft grunting]
Shh! Keep it down!
[yelping and squeaking]
[grunting]
[clattering, gasping]
[sighing]
Phew!
Hey, seen a jeweled box
about yea big?
No, what's in it?
A little something called
mind your own business.
I'll show you my business!
[grunting] Ah!
What are you looking at, buddy?
[gasping in delight]
My treasure!
Shh!
[roaring]
Sorceress hurt
PowerLid's feelings,
so PowerLid will hurt
everyone's everything!
[slamming]
[crazed roaring]
[Kai] Wait! PowerLid!
I used to be just like you!
Then you got second eye?
What? No.
No, I mean,
it used to be easier for me
to confront my enemies
than my feelings,
but I learned this--
lashing out dulls emotions,
but not for long.
Those bad feelings
come back worse than ever.
Then what solution?
Bash rocks?
[chuckling]
I wish it were that easy,
but no,
it's... communication.
[sighing heavily]
Gandy?
You were PowerLid's best friend,
then one day you supposed
to come on gem hunt,
never show up.
PowerLid try to find you.
You just gone.
You abandon PowerLid.
Not good friend.
[sighing heavily]
It was supposed to be
an a capella vocal practice,
but you scheduled a gem hunt
without asking.
It became "gem this,"
"gem that."
Gems crowded out
everything else in your brain.
You changed!
You change too!
You coconut now!
This isn't me, you big dummy!
This is my backup personality,
but... you're right.
I should have talked to you,
not just disappeared.
Sorry, PowPow.
PowerLid sorry too, Gandy.
Great.
Now, sorry
to cut this reunion short,
but we need to ring those bells.
No problem. You go.
Only cost six gems.
Friends discount.
But-but she apologized.
You made up!
Yes, nice,
but unrelated issue.
PowerLid,
you can't focus on us.
You've got to gather up
your gems!
What Red talk about?
My gems all safe
in nice crate right over--
Aah! My gems!
PowerLid coming for you!
Make you safe!
Run now. Run!
Run, run, run!
[PowerLid panting in distress]
[cackling] Rapton stays winning!
[quietly]
We can't let them get away.
Arrakore trusted us
to guard his treasure
while he creates the Arc Dragon.
He did? I don't
remember him saying that.
It was implied.
[mechanisms clicking]
Be sure to thank
the angry Djinn for Rapton
when he wakes up! Ha ha!
[quietly] We can't
let the bombs explode
and distract Arrakore!
[whispering] Obviously.
[roaring]
[exploding]
Phew!
[novelty car horn blaring]
Should we go after them?
No, we should wait
for Arrakore.
Your wait is over.
Did you do it?
Go see for yourself.
[growling roar]
Meanwhile, I'm going to sleep
for a week.
[groaning sleepily]
Well, what are we waiting for?
[Lloyd] We're getting close.
We should head down
before ThunderFang spots us.
[thudding heavily]
[Arin] The Well should be
right up there--
[deafening clang]
ThunderFang's
all over that Well
like a lattice crust
on a snowberry pie.
How are we supposed to get
the Unbidden Storm
down in there?
Even if we find a way
to distract him long enough,
he must have this place
heavily guarded.
[Arin] Like, by them?
[unearthly screeching]
[screeching]
H'yah!
Ha! H'yah!
[laughing] All right!
Prismatic armor works!
Remind me to thank Sora.
[Arin] If we get the chance.
Be brave like the ninja,
brave like the ninja...
I, Alfonzo Elias Frohicky,
Assistant Keeper
of the Monastery,
will not permit you to--
Permit me?
My strength permits me.
[wailing]
Haah!
[grunting with impact]
[groaning]
My family is in this Monastery,
and I'll defend them
to my last breath.
So not for long, then.
[growling]
Aah!
H'yah!
Haah!
[groaning]
Go!
Hide!
[growling]
I don't need a weapon
to destroy you.
I can defeat you
with my bare hands.
You are just as lost
as those children
you fail to protect!
H'yah!
[grunting with impact]
[groaning]
You will take me to Wu's--
What is so amusing?
Something's
coming from the east.
[grunting]
I once trapped a Source Dragon.
Am I to tremble
in front of a decrepit
old lizard
on her last legs?
A Tiger Tribe warrior
without honor?
Zarkar himself would be ashamed
to find his last descendant
sunk to--
[gasping]
A Source Dragon Icon?
Two icons? Impossible.
Send my greetings to Egalt.
H'yah!
[roaring in pain]
Hi-yah!
[groaning with impact]
Aah!
Now, show me to Wu's study.
[cackling]
Rapton would risk
a thousand henchmen's lives
for you,
the greatest treasure of all,
a rare Djinjagan variant.
My collection
is finally complete.
Incoming!
[unearthly shrieking]
Aah!
Whew!
I'd sure hate to be
whoever she's after.
[unearthly shrieking]
Spectral armor or not,
I don't know how much longer
these mechs can hold up.
Whoo whoo!
Whoa! [grunting with effort]
[slamming]
I'll hold them off!
Get down that well!
How?
Wait...
Bleckt said
there's a whole cavern
beneath the Well, right?
[unearthly shrieking]
H'yah!
[slamming]
-[unearthly shrieking]
-Help me!
You sure
this is the best ide--?
[unearthly shrieking]
[slamming]
-[rock crumbling]
-Wha...!
Arrakore and Zanth,
they did it!
[gasping] Look!
Okay.
Song-spell time.
Slow your roll, Mr. Eager.
Let's rehearse
and get this right.
♪ Hmm-hmm-hmm... ♪
♪ Da-da-da... ♪
♪ La-da-da
La-da-da-da... ♪
-That's not right!
-You're messing it up!
[Wyldfyre] You're both wrong!
It was [singing "La Cucaracha"]
[together]
That was Rapton's horn!
Oh, right.
Oh, no.
In all the chaos,
we've forgotten the song!
[humming spell song]
That's a Spell Song of Waking,
all right.
Very powerful magic.
Uh... one small problem.
Where are the bells?
Uh, bummer.
The bells have been
in Mysterium so long,
the natural magic of the land
must have transfigured them.
Meh, it happens.
Bells into doves,
purses into piglets,
shopping bags into
wandering theater troupes.
How are we supposed
to ring a dove?
[humming a melody]
[humming
competing melodies]
[grumbling a melody]
We can't keep going
back and forth.
We're running out of time!
You don't know the melody.
You weren't even there, Frak.
I listened
the first time you taught me.
I have perfect pitch?
[bell chiming]
[error tone buzzing]
[Sora] Looks like we only have
three chances...
and we've already wasted one.
[squawking]
[yelping] Aah!
[spluttering]
I never thought I'd say this,
but I wish Fugi-Dove were here.
Doves are the worst.
No self-respecting spellcaster
would have one as a familiar.
Now, Janet had a dove.
Trained it to befoul
my cauldron whenever I--
Wait, you say this Janet
trained her dove?
How?
Snacks.
All simple-minded creatures
are motivated by food.
[grumbling]
Oh, don't mention food.
I'm so hungry!
I could actually eat
these gross wafers Geo made.
[whimpering and munching]
[gagging] Ugh, never mind.
No, I'm not.
You have snacks?
Gimme those!
Come on...
Polly want a... this thing?
[dove cooing]
Come on, birdy, we need this!
[chirping a note]
It worked!
-[bell chiming]
-You got this!
Dominate those bells!
Raar!
[bells chiming]
[humming melody]
By all means, take your time.
Not like the world
is going to end!
[humming melody]
[bell chiming]
[error tone buzzing]
[Frak sighs]
One chance left.
I'll take it from here.
I can do it!
I only made one mistake.
Which I watched
and learned from.
Nope. You've each gone already.
My turn!
-Stop!
[chirping note]
[bell chiming]
-[chirping note]
-[bell chiming]
[chirping, chiming]
[chirping and chiming notes]
[tone reverberating]
[bells tolling waking spell]
[♪♪♪]
[growling]
[roaring]
Did it work?
Maybe?
Let's hope everyone else
is doing their part now.
[stones crumbling]
[Lloyd grunts with effort]
[coughing]
Arin!
[Arin] I'm okay!
Arin, I'm sorry.
I was so focused on
getting us down here,
I didn't think about
the consequences.
I'm fine, and look!
[Lloyd] Is that... ?
[Arin] Let's find out.
We're below
the Well of the Lost!
You did it!
Now we just need...
The Unbidden Storm!
I must have dropped it
in the fall!
[Lloyd]
It broke during the cave-in.
I ruined our last chance
to stop ThunderFang.
[cackling malevolently]
[♪♪♪]